Kekse
Hi there, my name is John Fish, and I'm a Harvard student.
I'm a freshman studying computer science, and this video is going to be a day
in my life.
And the first thing we're doing today, it's about 7.30 a.m., I'm going to go
grab some breakfast.
So Annenberg is Harvard's freshman dining hall, and honestly, it's like something out of Harry
Potter.
It's pretty cool.
God
morgon Luke Ok, det er nå 8.15 8.15 am Og min første klasse begynner på
9 Så jeg har 45 minutter Jeg har hjulpet for denne klasse som jeg ikke
har gjort enda Bare en liten bit, en pag Så jeg skal gjøre det, det
er svensk
Og det andre tinget jeg liker å gjøre i morgonen Er å planle ut min
dag Så jeg har en utviklingsbok, det er noe jeg kaller en liten dagligplanningsagenda, hvor
jeg skriver ut min skjelning for dagen, mine mål, min motivasjon, ting sånt.
Så jeg kommer til å gjøre det, og jeg kommer til å gjøre mitt hjemmelag,
og så kommer vi til klassen.
Alltså, så bare å gå med deg gjennom hva min skjelning kan se ut for
en dag.
Dette er min skjelning for dagen.
Du vet, våk opp, gjør noe hjemmelag, går til svensk, går til matematikk, har noe
mat, går til lektur for min CS-kurs i dag.
Det er en gudstekning, som bør være cool.
Then I work out, do some dinner, go to work, and then go to bed,
hopefully like 10pm.
That's the goal, that's one of my goals for today, is to hit 9 hours
of sleep.
I've already meditated, which is great.
I want to read around 50 pages of my book throughout the day.
And then of course, I want to film this video.
So this is a daily planner that I have personally designed, and that I'm actually
making.
I actually just had a company produce a bunch of them, and they're going to
be shipped to amazon hopefully within the next month and they'll be available on amazon
prime and stuff like that and so if you want to buy one i definitely
recommend signing up for my newsletter the link for that is in my description and
you'll be able to pick up one of these when they come out oh and
check out the cover on that bad boy look at that ooh ooh embossed logo
okay i should do my homework Upp til Sverige
nå.
Det er faktisk om 9.02, men jeg kommer til å være på tid, fordi en
av de interessante tingene om hvordan Harvard-klasser fungerer er at de alle begynner på Harvard-tiden,
som er 7 minutter over tid, eller 7 minutter over når klassen er forstått å
begynne.
Så jeg kommer til å være der på tid, selv om jeg kanskje kommer til
å være der om 9.06.
Det er en av de fleste klasser som vi har hatt i Sverige.
They all start on Harvard time, which is seven minutes past the hour, or seven
minutes past when the class is supposed to start.
So I'll be there on time, even though I'll probably get there at like 9.06.
There's Widener Library, by the way.
It's a pretty cool library.
Alright, so that was an hour of Swedish.
It is now 10 a.m., so I'm headed off to Linear Algebra.
It's across campus, so I'm going to kind of have to rush to get there
in seven minutes, but usually I'm able to do it in like six or seven.
So many tourists.
Alright, so rolling back from lunch now.
I've got about an hour before my next class, which is a guest lecture.
It's a computer science course, which is what the title of this video is.
Computer science student, that's me.
And so, yeah, I'm going to kill some time.
Maybe start an essay, maybe work on a couple problem sets.
Maybe edit a video, I don't know.
I've got a lot of things on my to-do list.
So the lecture today is for my functional programming class.
It's called CS51.
And it's a guest lecturer, which is kind of cool.
He's from Jane Street, which is like an investment firm, I believe.
And they use OCaml, which is like one of the only actual firms in the
world or companies that uses the language, which is the language that we use.
It's a functional programming language.
So I'm really interested to hear.
I don't even know what the lecture is going to be on, but I'm just...
I've heard that it's supposed to be one of the best lectures of the year
for the course So I'll actually go to this one in person Just gonna head
over there in like 50 minutes and in the meantime probably gonna edit a video
Very, very cool lecture and not just because they gave us free shirts, although that
was cool too, thanks Jane Street, but just a cool lecture.
Yeah, I thought it was actually pretty insightful in terms of just like cool like
programming practices that he gave us.
Things like how to write code that literally you can't express errors in, which I
thought was a very interesting concept.
idea being like you need to design your types so OCaml is a is a
typed language and when you're designing your custom types doing so in a way that
it is literally impossible to write invalid or to write an invalid state and the
examples that I gave with that were really interesting so now the next thing that
I have to do I have to go work out and I'm not allowed to
talk about that on camera on my YouTube channel.
So instead, here are just some cinematic shots that I took of Harvard and its
surrounding area.
Alright, back from working out, time to go grab a bite to eat for dinner
and then time to grind for a little bit.
Okay, so it's now 7.20pm and I've got a bunch of work to do.
So what I'm going to be working on right now is I've got an essay
that I need to be writing for tomorrow, just like a little rough draft.
I don't even think it's due until tomorrow at midnight.
Then I'm going to be starting a p-set.
So I have nothing really due tomorrow, which is great, but I'm just going to
be working on a bunch of different things.
Okay, so the essay that I'm writing, it's a literature review that is based off
of this book, Flow, by Mahali Chikmahali.
I think that's how you say his last name, but correct me if I'm wrong.
The fundamental premise of the book is how do you find happiness in a world
where we really struggle to do that?
It seems like everyone wants to be happy, right?
But over the thousands of years that we've progressed, we haven't really become that much
happier as people.
And so the question is, well, what does make you happy?
And in Flow, that question is answered with the idea of meaningful work.
that is if you have a task that fulfills chikma hali breaks it down into
eight different things eight different categories that have task bits and then it's a it's
a flow activity hence the name flow so you can apply this to anything and
chikma hali applies it to an entire life saying that if you create one goal
for your entire life and then you structure your life around that with goals and
with sub-goals and so on, then you can have one life that is just a
flow experience, and therefore it will be an enjoyable experience and a happy experience.
Now, what I'm looking at in my essay is how do you apply that as
a student to the education system?
Because I believe that the education system is, well, it's pretty messed up, to be
honest.
I feel like a lot of students are miserable, and that shouldn't be the case.
Like, school should be an enjoyable experience.
It should be fun.
And I think that you can make it fun, and I think that there's a
way to do that with flow.
So, I'm gonna go write my essay, and then once I've written my essay, there
will be a video essay component to it.
That's actually part of the course, which is really cool.
We go to one of the studios on campus, and we film a mini TED
talk.
So if you're interested, I'll upload that video to this channel.
So if you're not subscribed, definitely subscribe because, well, hopefully it'll be a useful video
essay for you.
And if not, I upload video essays every week, so I'm sure there will be
something in there that you find useful.
Anyways, I'm going to go write this essay.
Okay, the essay is going pretty well.
I've been writing for about an hour.
I'm getting a little tired, though, so I'm going to change gears.
I'm going to do some math for a bit because I've got a problem set
due in a couple days.
So I'm going to do a little bit of linear algebra, some four-year series.
Four year.
Four years.
I'm going to do some linear algebra.
Now another thing that I can imagine a lot of people are wondering is that
for a computer science student, I didn't do a whole lot of coding today.
And that's actually true, and it's kind of a factor of Harvard being a liberal
arts school.
So the courses that I'm taking are Swedish Expos, which is a writing course, Linear
Algebra, CS51.
That's it.
There's just four courses.
And if you're coming from a technical college background like me, coming from Canada, where
pretty much every school is a technical college and you take like eight courses a
semester and they're all pretty much given to you, yeah, it'd be kind of ridiculous
to be taking a course like Swedish or to be taking a writing course.
But I kind of love it because, yes, programming is fun.
But I think that overall, the point of school is to make you develop as
a person.
Like you're trying to make people that are better members of society.
And I don't think that becoming only a better coder will make you a better
person necessarily.
I think that there's so much more to life than that.
So it's like nine o'clock, well, nine oh five, and I'm going to start reading
and brushing my teeth and getting ready for bed because I try and be in
bed for 10 o'clock because nine hours of sleep, waking up at seven, just got
to go to bed early.
But But before I head to bed, I'd like to talk to you about the
sponsor of this video.
As a computer science student, sometimes listening to the lectures isn't enough for me to
understand the things that I'm trying to learn.
To actually understand a concept, I have to reinforce what's being taught by doing problems,
and that's why I love the sponsor of this video, Brilliant.org.
Brilliant has a wide variety of interesting math and science problems and courses that can
help you to both reinforce what you're learning and to learn new things.
For example, when my CS51 class went over red-black binary trees, I was able to
work through the course that Brilliant has on them to clear up my confusion from
the lecture.
And best of all, when I got problems wrong, I was able to look at
a detailed solution and understand what went wrong in my thought process, and then fix
it.
Then when it actually came to implementing a red-black tree, I didn't have to go
searching through all sorts of reference materials.
Brilliant had taught me all of the concepts that I needed to know.
It's genuinely a really effective system.
So if you're interested in signing up for Brilliant.org, check out the link in my
description to sign up for free.
And also, the first 200 of my viewers that decide to upgrade will actually get
20% off their premium annual plan.
It is now 10pm, so I'm going to head to bed because I'm getting up
at 7 tomorrow and one of my goals for the day was to hit 9
hours of sleep.
Yeah, pretty uneventful day, pretty average day.
I hope that you enjoyed this video of a day in my life.
I hope that you got to see a little bit of insight into what it
is to be a student in freshman year at Harvard.
And yeah, thank you so much for watching.
I will see you in the next video.
Don't forget to subscribe if you haven't already because I make videos every week, sometimes
probably more.
Okay, bye.